returnpath.com 2006-10-17

# Return Path Solutions for Increased Email Delivery, Performance

| 

**Download our Glossary of Email Terms:**

**Download our Corporate Overview:**

|  | 

**Effective December 2003  
RETURN PATH PRIVACY STATEMENT**

| 

---  

We know that your privacy is important to you. At Return Path, we're committed to helping you manage and protect it. We take privacy very seriously, and have taken many steps to help safeguard the personal information we collect from you at this Web site.

To demonstrate our commitment, we have agreed to disclose our information practices, and have them reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe and BBBOnLine, a Better Business Bureau program. Return Path is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program and the BBBOnLine Privacy and Dispute Resolution Program. TRUSTe and BBBOnLine are independent, non-profit organizations whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. To that end, our privacy statement will tell you about:

  * The organization collecting information at this Web site. 
  * The information we collect. 
  * How it is used. 
  * With whom it may be shared. 
  * What choices you have regarding the use and distribution of this information. 
  * The security procedures in place to protect it. 
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, contact Return Path at [privacy@returnpath.net](mailto:privacy@returnpath.net). If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or if your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, you should contact:

  * [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php), TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve your concerns. 

To read our complete Privacy Statement, Click here.

Thank you for using Return Path.

Sincerely,

Matt Blumberg  
CEO  
Return Path, Inc. 

**RETURN PATH PRIVACY STATEMENT**  

Protecting your privacy is very important to Return Path. We offer services that help consumers manage their email relationships with personal and commercial contacts. We know that you're concerned with privacy on the Internet, and we've taken many steps to help safeguard your information.

This privacy statement is provided to inform you of our privacy policy and practices and of the choices you can make about the way your personal information is collected online and how that information is used. By personal information we mean information about you collected through this Web site, including your name, email addresses, home or work addresses, or any other information combined with these identifiers.

**The organization collecting information at this Web site:**  
Return Path collects personal information about you when you sign-up for Return Path's email change of address service, email forwarding service, or contact management service, or when you sign up for special promotions offered on our Web site, or when you use our email finder service. We collect this information either directly at our Web site, [www.returnpath.net](http://www.returnpath.net/), or through a co-registration page at a partner Web site, or through a pop-up window deployed on a partner Web site. We may combine the information about you that we collect with information we obtain from business partners or other companies. 

**Information we collect:**  
Return Path asks you for information that enables us to provide the services you wish to use.

  * This information may include your old email address, your new email address, your name, or your residential or work address. 
  * If you wish to use Return Path Email Forwarding we will ask you to provide us with the password for your old email account. Your email password is necessary for Return Path to access and re-route email from your old email account to your new email account. We may also ask you to provide a valid credit card number and expiration date so we can authenticate your identity prior to activating the email forwarding service and for billing purposes. 
  * Return Path collects information about your interactions with our services and our Web site, including the date and time you submit your registration for our services, as well as other administrative information that helps Return Path prevent people from misusing our system. 
  * If you choose to send an email notification card to friends, family and business contacts informing them of your email address change, Return Path will collect the email addresses of the intended recipients, and if you choose to include such information, a brief, personal message. To facilitate the use of Return Path email address change notification cards, you may upload your email address book from your old email account. Return Path will not use the recipients' email addresses other than to deliver a notification card (although the recipients may be presented with an opportunity to register with Return Path themselves). 
  * If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask him for the friend's email address. Return Path will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting him to visit the site. Return Path stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. The friend may contact [Return Path Support](http://returnpath.custhelp.com/) to request the suppression of this information in our database. 
  * If you are using Return Path Email Finder to look for someone, we will ask you for your first and last name, as well as the last known email address for the person you are seeking. We request your first and last name to identify you to the individual whose email address you are seeking. 

**How we use this information:**  
Return Path uses the collected information for the following general purposes: to fulfill the services you have requested, inform you of your account activity, customize the services or content you receive, contact you, improve our services, conduct research, and provide anonymous reporting for internal and external clients. Return Path treats your personal information as confidential and does not disclose it or use it except as permitted by you, as described in this privacy policy, or as required by law, subpoena, court order, legal process or a warrant.

  * When you register with Return Path, we send out confirmation emails to both your old and new email addresses. We do this to validate your registration and to help prevent people from misusing our service. Our confirmation emails provide instructions on how to activate your registration, or cancel it as appropriate. 
  * Return Path, on occasion, surveys selected users regarding their use of email and our services, as well as their interests and/or preferences so that we may continue to enhance our services to best serve all our customers. Should we ask you to participate in one of these surveys, your participation is completely at your option. 
  * Your new email address serves as your account log-in ID. You should use a new email address that only you have access to for this purpose, if at all possible, to reduce the risk of someone misusing your Return Path account. 
  * If we are served with a civil subpoena seeking personal information about a Return Path user, we will use reasonable efforts to notify the specified user of the request prior to disclosure of such personal information, so as to allow the user the opportunity to oppose the subpoena. 
  * Return Path may engage third parties to perform analysis or data processing of our databases that involves access to your personal information, in order to better provide you with the services for which you joined. If Return Path does so, it will ensure that such parties are contractually required to keep the information confidential and not to use it in any way other than is necessary to perform their work for Return Path. 
  * If you register with Return Path, you give Return Path permission to use the information we have told you we collect here, for the purposes we have stated here, according to the options you indicate through the Return Path emails and on our Web site. 

**Information we share:**

  * Return Path maintains a directory of email address changes to help you regain contact with businesses and individuals with whom you have a previous email relationship. Once you register with Return Path, you decide who gets access to your information. Individuals who have lost contact with you at an old email address may request your updated email address. Alternatively, businesses may send us a list of email addresses in an attempt to re-contact customers or subscribers whose email addresses may have changed. Return Path will notify you each time an individual or business requests your updated email address, providing you with seven days to decline the request. If after seven days you have not declined the request, the request will be considered approved by you, and your email address will be provided to the requester, whose use of your new email address will be covered by their privacy policy. Return Path only works with businesses that practice permission marketing. If you are concerned about the privacy practices of a business that has requested your new email address using the Return Path service, please notify us at Return Path Privacy at [privacy@returnpath.net](mailto:privacy@returnpath.net). 
  * If you choose to use Return Path's optional, fee-based, email forwarding service, we will collect email sent to your old email address, re-address the email, and forward it to your new email address. Your old email account must be active while using this service. In addition, Return Path sends an automatic reply email message to the email sender indicating that the email message has been forwarded. This message contains a link to the Return Path Email Finder Directory, where the sender can submit a request for your new email address. Return Path will send you an email message requesting that you approve the request. Return Path will only provide your new email address to the sender if you click the acceptance link in the request message. 
  * As part of the Return Path email forwarding service, emails sent to your old email account that are subsequently forwarded to your new email account will be deleted from your old email account. The Return Path email forwarding service deletes these old email copies to prevent the inbox of your old email account from running out of space. 
  * Return Path may gather information about the email traffic of customers including the number and size of messages received, the domain name and address of the email sender, and the number and size of email attachments. 
  * Return Path uses a widely available "spam" filtering application to limit the amount of unsolicited commercial email that is transmitted through the Return Path email forwarding service. This spam filtering application will automatically scan the email message for specific words or phrases. Messages deemed to be spam will not be forwarded. 
  * As needed to provide the service, Return Path will temporarily store messages for a short time. When messages are received they are stored in a queue for processing. Once messages are delivered to the final destination at your new ISP, the messages are deleted. Return Path will not read or disclose to third parties private email communications that are transmitted using Return Path services except as required to operate the service or as otherwise authorized by law. 
  * If you choose to send an email greeting card to notify others of your email address change, Return Path will share your first name, last name, and email address with the recipients of the greeting card. Return Path will not use the recipients' names or email addresses other than to deliver the greeting card (although the recipients may be presented with an opportunity to register for Return Path's free email change of address service). 

**Our use of cookies:**  
A "cookie" is a small data file transferred by a Web site to your computer's hard drive. Return Path sends cookies when you surf our site or register for certain services. Accepting cookies used on our Web site does not give Return Path access to your personal information, but we may use the cookies to identify your computer. Cookies are typically classified as either "session" cookies or "permanent" cookies.

"Session" cookies do not stay on your computer after you leave our Web site or close your browser. The aggregate information collected permits us to analyze traffic patterns on our site. This can enable us over time to provide a better experience on our site by improving content or personalization and making our site easier to use. 

"Permanent" cookies are those that remain on your computer. They are used to facilitate shopping, personalization and registration services. For example, cookies can keep track of what you have selected to purchase as you continue to shop and allow you to enter your password only once on Web pages where a log-in is required. "Permanent" cookies can be manually removed by the user. 

Currently Return Path only uses session cookies.

Most browsers automatically accept cookies by default, but you can usually refuse cookies or selectively accept certain cookies by adjusting the preferences in your browser. If you turn off cookies, there may be some features of our site that will not be available to you and some Web pages may not display properly. You can find information on popular browsers and how to adjust your cookie preferences at the following Web sites:

Microsoft Internet Explorer: <http://www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.htm>  
Netscape Navigator: <http://www.netscape.com/legal_notices/cookies.html>

**Our use of web beacons:**  
Some Return Path Web pages, banner ads and HTML-formatted email newsletters use Web beacons in conjunction with cookies to compile aggregate statistics about Web site usage. A Web beacon is an electronic image, called a single-pixel (1x1), an action tag or a clear GIF. Web beacons can recognize certain types of information on a visitor's computer, such as a visitor's cookie number, time and date of a page view, and whether the visitor is using an email reader that understands HTML email messages. This information helps us understand and improve the effectiveness of our web-based communications. You may render some Web beacons unusable by rejecting their associated cookies.

**Our use of third party media companies:**  
We may display advertisements from third parties. Third-party ad-serving companies control which ads are shown. These ad-serving companies may use their own cookies to collect non-personally identifiable information from you. Some Return Path email newsletters may also be delivered on Return Path's behalf by third party media companies that use the same technologies. In either case, this data is used by the third party media companies to measure advertising and content interest and relevance. To prevent third party media companies from placing cookies on your computer, you will need to visit each media company's Web site and use their cookie removal process or set your browser cookie filter accordingly.

**Your choices:**  
As a Return Path member, you have access to, and appropriate control over, the data that Return Path maintains about you. We provide you with easy access to the information maintained about you in the Return Path database in a format that is easy to understand. 

To revise or edit your personally identifiable information, simply go to My Account on the Return Path Web site. Use your new email address as your log-in ID. Return Path, upon recognizing your valid log-in ID, will send an email to your new email address containing the link for access to My Account. Requests for deletion of certain key information, such as email address, may require closing the account.

Most requests for access to personal data are processed within seconds of being made through the Return Path Web interface. Some requests may take up to a few days to process, and the results may be delivered by email. Any other questions should be addressed to [Return Path Support](http://returnpath.custhelp.com/). Information about a member may be withheld or exempted from deletion if this is required by law or is part of a fraud investigation.

**To Unsubscribe:**  
If you decide that you do not wish to participate in our service, you can unsubscribe by clicking on the link provided in any email message Return Path sends you and following the directions provided. Additionally, you can remove your account information directly from the Return Path Web site by going to My Account, after logging in, and clicking the link marked "Remove Old Addresses". Or you may contact [Return Path Support](http://returnpath.custhelp.com/).

**Security Safeguards:**  
Return Path is committed to protecting the information you provide us. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of the information, Return Path has in place appropriate physical and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect. We hold our employees and partners accountable for maintaining the privacy and integrity of our users' information.

Return Path may engage employees, contractors, and other companies to perform work that involves access to personal information. If Return Path does so, it will ensure that such parties are contractually required to keep the information confidential and not to use it in any way other than as is necessary to perform their work for Return Path.

We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information. SSL encryption is designed to make the information unreadable by anyone but us. This security measure is working when you see either the symbol of an unbroken key or closed lock (depending on your browser) on the bottom of your browser window.

To access the information Return Path holds about you, use your new email address as your log-in ID. Return Path, upon recognizing your valid log-in ID will send an email to your new email address, containing the link for access to My Account. If you allow others to have access to your new email address box--that is, allow them to access and read your email--they may be able to gain access to your Return Path account. To maintain the highest level of security for your Return Path account, you should not provide others with access to your email address box.

**Children's Privacy:**  
Return Path is committed to protecting the privacy needs of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children's online activities and interests. Return Path does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and Return Path does not target its Web sites to children under 13. 

**Business Transfers or Bankruptcy:**  
As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy companies or assets. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. In the unlikely event that Return Path or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will be one of the transferred assets. Return Path users will be notified of such business transfer or bankruptcy and be given the opportunity to opt-out of any such transfer. For more information see the "Notification of Changes" section below.

**Notification of Changes:**  
If there are changes to the terms of Return Path's Privacy Statement, we will post those changes and update the revision date in this document on Return Path's Web site prior to implementing those changes, so you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it, and what choices you have. For material changes to this Statement, Return Path will post an announcement on our site and provide email notification to affected customers. The foregoing policy is effective as of June 2003.

**Contacting us:**  
We value your opinions. If you have comments or questions about our privacy policy, please send them to Return Path Privacy at [privacy@returnpath.net](mailto:privacy@returnpath.net), or contact:

Return Path, Inc.  
304 Park Avenue South, 7th Floor  
New York, New York 10010  
Phone: 212-905-5500  
Fax: 212-905-5501

Company | [Delivery Assurance ](http://www.senderscore.com/) | Email List Quality | [Customer Acquisition](http://www.postmasternetwork.net/) | Strategic Solutions  | Client Login  
Copyright 2000-2006 Return Path, Inc., All Rights Reserved. Return Path is a registered trademark of Return Path, Inc.
